

## Profile

I create scalable and modern web and mobile experiences. I love to play with bleeding edge technology and I live to tinker and learn. My tech stack is always evolving. I am driven by curiosity and a need to solve difficult problems.

# Employment History

## Tech Lead at NearOnes, Amsterdam

May 2019 - August 2019

NearOnes is a local community two-way marketplace connecting people who need help with daily tasks, with those who would gladly and reliably help. I was the technical lead during their first months of building the product. I was responsible for early software architecture, infrastructure choices and the development of an MVP. I used React Native, Expo, Serverless and other tools.

## Web Developer at Vettvangur, Reykjavík

2017 - 2018

I was a full stack web developer working on various sites for some of our clients. We built on top of Umbraco, which is a .NET CMS. On the front end we used React, TypeScript and Angular.

## Full-stack Developer at Vivaldi, Reykjavík

2014 - 2017

Vivaldi is building one of the worlds most advanced web browsers. It's designed with power users in mind. My main task at Vivaldi was to develop the technical aspects of their community. I worked on Vivaldi's product and community websites. Responsibilities include cross device compatability, security, SEO, infrastructure, frontend and backend development. I also worked on centralized authentication (OAuth2, OpenID, SAML). My tools of choice were JavaScript, Node.js, Express, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB and React.

### Web Developer at Spyr.is, Reykjavík

March 2013 - May 2014

An Icelandic interactive community driven journalism website which allowed readers to submit questions directed at specific entities such as organizations, government agencies and officials etc. We published articles from the responses. I took over the web project from a digital agency and worked with Spyr in-house. I worked on front and back-end as well as infrastructure and some minor design work. Our stack was a PHP and JS.

#### **Details**

+354 8473439

s@steinar.io

## Links

Website LinkedIn

#### **Skills**

React

Nodejs

Flutter

PHP

DevOps

CI/CD

.NET

**React Native** 

## Developer, IT, Service Rep at Hringiðan, Reykjavík

2010 - 2013

I started work as a service rep, part time with my studies. Responsibilities include troubleshooting internet issues, selling internet and phone services. I eventually moved on to web hosting, which led to some of my first web development work. I also worked a bit on company intranet sites in ASP.NET, C# as well as sysadmin work, managing MS IIS and DNS servers.

## Education

## MSc Computer Science, Leiden University, Leiden, NL

2017 - Present

Specialization in Advanced Data Analytics. Learning about AI and Natural Computing. Especially interested in Neural Networks, Evolutionary Algorithms and Reinforcement Learning. I worked on a thesis on optimizing neural network committee machines for object recognition in video.

## BSc Computer Science, Reykjavík University, Reykjavík

2010 - 2014

I dipped my toes into various fields within computer science but my primary focus was on web development and software engineering. I also took a few marketing and branding courses.

## **1** References

### René Roskamp from Holland Startup

r.roskamp@hollandstartup.com · +31 6229 589 08

### Elmar Gunnarsson from Vettvangur

elmar@vettvangur.is · +354 868 2798

## María Þorgeirsdóttir from Vivaldi

maria@vivaldi.com